Alexander **Ottenhoff**

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER · TEAM LEAD · FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

Kew, Victoria, Australia

🚢 25 November 1987 🖪 (+61) 434-155-289 🖾 alexander.ottenhoff@gmail.com 😱 AlexanderOttenhoff 🛅 Alexander Ottenhoff

Summary _

I'm a senior full stack software engineer with over 10 years of experience in building web and mobile applications. I have a strong background in computer science and electrical engineering, and have experience working in a variety of industries, including mining, biotech, and computer security. I have worked in both startups and large corporations, and have experience leading teams of developers and working closely with product teams to deliver high quality software products.

Experience _

Lead Software Engineer (Mobile Applications)

Melbourne, Victoria, Australia

September 2023 - October 2024

ZETIFI

• Led a team of developers to build a mobile application for Zetifi devices

- Worked closely with the product team to define the product roadmap
- Developed Serverless backend services in AWS to support the mobile application
- Technologies: React Native, Typescript, AWS Lambda, Python, FastAPI, AWS DynamoDB, AWS Timestream

Senior Software Engineer (Fullstack)

Perth, Western Australia, Australia

BHP

July 2021 - August 2023

- Developed a dashboard to visualise safety data across all of BHP's operations
- Worked with data engineers to build a data pipeline to support the dashboard
- · Migrated the legacy dashboard from Javascript to Typescript, implemented a new UI design system, and modernised the codebase
- Technologies: React, Typescript, D3, C#, .NET Core, Snowflake, PostgreSQL, Docker

Senior Software Engineer (Frontend)

's-Hertogenbosch, Netherlands

March 2020 - June 2021

- Developed a web application to visualise and analyse immunogenomics data
- Worked with bioinformaticians to run scaled down versions of complex bioinformatics algorithms on subsets of the data in the browser
- Technologies: React, Typescript, D3, WebAssembly, Rust, Docker, Kubernetes, Python

Cofounder / CTO Paris, France

BASELIST

June 2019 - December 2019

- Co-founded Baselist, a platform for finding real time price information on supermarket goods across France and optimizing shopping lists based on the user's location
- Pitched to Y Combinator, but was not accepted
- Technologies: React, Typescript, Node.JS, Express, PostgreSQL, Docker, AWS

Senior Software Engineer (Backend)

Paris, France

MICROSOFT

September 2018 - March 2019

- Worked on the integration of AI services into Microsoft's Power Apps platform
- Developed demo applications to showcase the capabilities of the AI services
- **Technologies**: C#, .NET Core, Azure Cognitive Services, Power Apps

Software Engineer (Frontend)

Paris, France

June 2016 - August 2018

SQREEN

• Developed a web application to visualise security data for Sgreen's customers

- Worked closely with the product team to define the product roadmap
- Implemented a new UI design system and modernised the codebase
- Technologies: React, Typescript, D3, Python, Flask, PostgreSQL

Cofounder / CTO Paris, France

SHERLOCK July 2015 - July 2016

· Co-founded Sherlock, a platform for finding and making appointments with healthcare professionals while travelling

• Won the national AFDEL (now Numeum) award in the category "Digital Innovation" (jury: Dassault Systèmes & Microsoft) in January 2016.

Software Engineer (Backend)

Berlin, Germany

ZAPPCHOICE

February 2015 - December 2015

• Developed the backend of the TimeZapp mobile quiz application

Software Engineer (Fullstack)

Berlin, Germany

LIMEMAKERS

January 2014 - January 2015

• Developed custom algorithms for generating customisable 3D printable models of jewellery and mobile phone cases based on user input

Electronic Engineer (Control Systems + Automation)

Perth, Western Australia

FLSMIDTH

November 2007 - June 2013

Skills_____

Programming Typescript, Javascript, Python, C#, Java, C++, Rust, Haskell

Languages

Frameworks React, Node.JS, Express, FastAPI, Flask, .NET Core

Tools Docker, **Kubernetes**, **D3**, Git, Jest, Postman, Unity

Cloud Platforms AWS, Microsoft Azure, Google Cloud Platform

Databases PostgreSQL, SQLite, MongoDB, AWS DynamoDB, AWS Timestream, MySQL, Snowflake

Spoken Languages English, French

Education _

University of Western Australia

Perth, Western Australia, Australia

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND B.E. IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

2006 - 2012